Smit Nirmal

🗣 M1V3C5, Canada 🔀 smitmnirmal@gmail.com 🥆 smitnirmal3597.github.io 📞 +1 (226) 759-3597

in linkedin.com/in/smitnirmal 😯 github.com/smitnirmal3597

Full-Stack Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in software development process. Strong knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming Languages, Data Structures and Algorithms. Understanding of SDLC to deliver quality and consistency in performance. True team player with well-developed analytical, problem-solving, interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills acquired through professional work experience.



Education

Master of Applied Computing, *University of Windsor*

Jan 2019 - Aug 2020

Bachelors of Computer Engineering, Ganpat University

Aug 2014 - May 2018



Skills

Languages

Java, JavaScript, C#, Python, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Database

MySQL, MS SQL Server, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, **Firebase**

Frameworks

Angular, Node.js, React, Express.js, .NET, .NET Core, Entity Framework, Ionic, Flask

Project/Code Management Tools

Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps, Agile, Scrum

Cloud Tools

AWS, Microsoft Azure, Heroku

Others

Nginx, jQuery, JSON, XML, Postman, Chrome Dev Tools, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins



Professional Experience

Software Consultant, BDO Canada

Mar 2021 – Present

Technologies: C#, .Net Core, Angular, HTML, SCSS, TypeScript, SQL Server, Azure DevOps, JIRA, Jenkins

- Understand and help refine un-stated requirements & work with the Development Manager, Business Analyst, and Project Manager to define software requirements and to assess the feasibility of solutions within time constraints
- Delivering development activities on time and on budget per project plan by producing quality code that is secure, reliable, reusable, and scalable
- · Participate in pull-request reviews and help team members to solve their technical difficulties

Programmer Analyst-Intern, Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

Technologies: Angular, Python, C#, ASP.NET, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, Apache ActiveMQ, Redis

- Responsible for developing micro-services in Angular, ASP.NET, Spring Boot and Python, also containerized them using Docker and orchestrated using Kubernetes
- Built back-end REST APIs using Flask and .NET; performed Unit and Integration testing
- · Duties included meeting with business partners, scrum masters and QA to identify and groom new functionality, upgrade existing functionality and system design changes in Agile-Scrum environment

Software Developer (Part-time), Bidja Innovations Inc.

Jan 2019 – Dec 2019

Technologies: Angular, Node.js, Ionic, Apache Cordova, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, JSON, Bitbucket

- Day to day duty included developing mobile application which connects to CNC machine and fetches live JSON data using Rest API; updated and maintained the data in firebase database
- Designed User Interface using web technologies such as Angular, Bootstrap 4, Ionic framework, HTML and CSS
- Utilized Apache Cordova to add native-app functionalities by ensuring that application is Android/iOS compatible
- Collaborated remotely with multiple team members in order to meet deliverable on time using GitHub

Achievements

- Participated in various academic coding competitions and secured top ranks in many of them
- Helped out participants during the coding competition for queries related to technical problems, provided resources for an event
- Demonstrated various professional skills while working at Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan